SHUBHAM JAIN

New Delhi, India

Email- shubhamjain0294@gmail.com

DOB- October 02, 1994

Contact No. - +91-9871904016

LinkedIn: https://in.linkedin.com/in/shubhamjain0294

Personal Website-itsShubhamJain.github.io

Professional Summary

Pursuing Master of Business Administration (Full Time) aiming to specialize in Human Resources Management (HRM) and Marketing Management. To work devotedly for the organization with great pride in the profession where my knowledge is transitioned. To contribute towards the growth of the organization through my academic knowledge and 4 years of corporate experience.

Education

 Master of Business Administration-Full Time (Centre of Management Studies, Jamia Millia Islamia University, Delhi)
 [Jan 2021-Present]

 B.Tech-Electronics and Communication Engineering (AIACTR, Guru Gobind Singh Indraprastha University, Delhi), CPI-74.50

[Aug 2012-Jun 2016]

• Intermediate(12th)- Lovely Public Sr. Sec. School, Delhi, C.B.S.E. Percentage-83.40 [May 2012]

• Matriculation(10th)- Lovely Public Sr. Sec. School, Delhi, C.B.S.E. Percentage-85.10 [May 2010]

Management/Technical Skills

- HP UFT (Adv. QTP), HP ALM, SOAP UI
- VB-script, Unix, Putty, C++, SQL Query, GitHub
- HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap Ajax, JQuery
- MS Word, MS Excel, MS PowerPoint, MS Outlook
- Test script development, execution
- Team Foundation Server
- Quality Assurance
- Gathering requirements

Work Experience and Internships

Test Automation Engineer

[Dec 2016-Jan 2021]

TATA Consultancy Services- Glaxo Smith Kline (UK) Domain-Life Sciences

- Over 4 years of experience in software testing of Client/Server and web based applications using structured methodologies. Very good experience in writing System Test Cases, Test Plans, executing Test Scripts, reporting defects and preparing Test Result reports.
- Involving experience in entire QA Life Cycle, which includes Designing, Developing and Execution of the entire QA process and documentation of Test Plans, Test Cases, Test Scenarios and Test Scripts for the web and Client/Server applications. Experienced in Manual, Integration, Regression and System Testing using automated testing tools in the web-based applications.
- Experienced in testing applications using the automated testing tools like Micro Focus Unified Functional Testing/ALM by writing Automation Test Scripts using VB-Script.
- Experienced in testing applications manually using tools like Micro Focus Unified Functional Application Lifecycle Management (ALM).
- Proficient in preparing Automation Test Suite for SOAP request using API Testing.

Web Designer Intern

Scaledesk Web Studio (Noida)

[Aug 2016-Oct 2016]

- Front End Web Designer- Made ecommerce websites using WordPress and Woo Commerce as a plugin.
- Designed web pages using HTML, CSS, Bootstrap and jQuery.

Digital Content Curator

Zolo Technologies (Noida)

[Apr 2016-Jul 2016]

- Experienced in writing quality content for the website of Services provider startup based in Noida.
- Experienced in curating content digitally for the startup
- Experienced in Digital/Social Media Marketing

Academic Projects

Major Project

Garima Srivastava (Asst. Prof.)[Jan 2016]

• Successfully implemented project- Performance Analysis of LTE & LTE Advance Systems using system level simulation.

Minor Project

Dr. Ravindra Kumar Sharma (Prof. HOD) [Aug 2015]

• Successfully implemented project-Smart Parking Applications using RFID (Radio Frequency Identification) Technology.

SAMUDRA-AUV

Dr. Rajveer Yadhuvanshi (Asst. Prof.)[Sep 2013-Mar 2015]

(System for Autonomous Marine Underwater Detection and Research Activities)

- Designed Mechanical models of Internal frame, Outer frame, Hull and various other parts using CATIA Software.
- Made Concept Development Report and added designs of mechanical models in the report.

Extra-Curricular

- Volunteer- Teach India, CSR Initiative by TIMES OF INDIA and BRITISH COUNCIL
- Taught spoken English to under privileged youth.
- Robotics- Coordinator of event-"SNIFFER LFR" in Proscenium (College Technical Fest).
- Attended workshops on Cloud Computing and Python Coding and Scripting.
- Member of Public relations team in Conversance-2014 (College cultural Fest).
- Catharsis- Environment awareness program, served as an Associate.
- Sahara Force India-Team Member in Pit Stop Challenge an event organized to promote F1 Racing held at IIT Delhi.
- Khel AIACTR- Organized event "200m race" and member of College's Discipline team.

Interests

• Playing Table Tennis, Listening music, Reading.

Declaration

I hereby declare that all the information furnished above is true and correct to the best of my knowledge and belief. (SHUBHAM JAIN)